Cage McGehee Johnson

cagejohnson.com 830-613-1712 cagejsn@gmail.com



Cage is an *outcome oriented* Senior Software Engineer with 6 years professional software experience. He brings a creative perspective to technology organizations. His wide technical knowledge allows him to function accurately in any area of a technology product, and his interpersonal skills enable him to influence others and drive change within organizations. He has a track record of leading teams to meet their goals and pushes the team to focus on what matters most for the big picture.

Education

The University of Texas at Austin | May 2017 Bachelor of Business Administration Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering

Experience

Senior Consultant - Slalom Consulting April 2018 - Present

While at Slalom, I was a client-facing consultant. My primary responsibility was delivering projects. Additionally, I managed 3 direct reports and led our internal volunteering organization.

Client Projects

Data Science for Data Governance Org.

- Built a tool to identify duplicate datasets (out of 50k different datasets) for data stewards.
- Prototyped a clustering solution in python (scikit, numpy, etc.) to cluster similar datasets based on column name & type.
- Productized the model, building a streamlit dashboard for business users to interact with the data product.

Data Engineering for a Customer 360 Data Product

- Contributed to development of a multi-stage data pipeline giving a "canonical" view of customers in a company with hundreds of CRM systems.
- Reduced bad merges by building a test suite for our database migrations.
- Enabled team to hit critical milestones by debugging and solving persistent cloud networking and memory consumption issues.
- Led design of a configurable data-transforming python application.

Customer Data Platform (A "Bring your own Data" marketing product)

- Led Engineering Team for a re-design of a Customer Data Platform Architecture your that was too complex and became unmaintainable.
- Influenced Architecture for the hyper-configurable ETL at the heart of a the product.
- Designed and built all CI/CD pipelines in Gitlab CI including Code Quality integrations.
- Designed and built Integration Tests which would stand as acceptance of completed milestones.

Billing for a Global Digital Advertising Product

- Led the Engineering Team to design and deliver a major change in tax accounting rules, including changes in several applications and requiring backward & forward compatibility.
- Contributed to a re-platforming of mission critical billing ETLs from on-prem Oozie to cloud-based Airflow.
- Modernized a suite of java applications from Spring / Tomcat to Containerized Spring Boot.
- Improved QE & deployment processes by building pipelines and tools to automate error-prone manual tasks.

Native iOS app leveraging ARKit

- Contributed to design and development of an app for AT&T's "field engineers" which allowed them to 3d scan and annotate AT&T owned assets
- Identified ARKit optimization which allowed us to store bigger ARKit "Scans"
- Built 3D cropping feature for users to trim "Scans".

Quality Assurance Engineer - Mutual Mobile September 2017 - April 2018

- Authored & executed Test Plans for a custom mobile app.
- Implemented bug fixes in Java for Android mobile app.

Founder - Desk

August 2016 - May 2017

 Led a team of software engineers to design, develop, and sell an app on Apple's App Store.

Leadership Experience

Division Leader - Camp Champions May 2017 - August 2017

- Led 12 counselors to ensure an excellent camp experience for 150 twelve to fourteen year old campers.
- Communicated with parents and collaborated with counselors to aid in camper's character development.
- Planned and coordinated age group specific activities.

Director - Longhorn Entrepreneurship Agency May 2016 - May 2017

- Acquired dedicated space on campus for a student-run entrepreneurship space.
- Led effort to raise \$16k for on-campus entrepreneurship space.
- Coordinated the Fall UT Austin Startup Job Fair with 350 student

Technologies

Python: Advanced
Java: Advanced
Golang: Advanced
Bash: Advanced
git: Advanced
Docker: Advanced
TypeScript: Intermediate
AWS: Intermediate
GCP: Intermediate
Vue: Intermediate
Django: Intermediate
PostgreSQL: Intermediate
Airflow: Intermediate
SQL: Intermediate

Skills

Engineering Team Lead
Backend Engineering
Frontend Engineering
Quality Engineering
Data Engineering
Public Cloud Architecture
Data Modeling
Data Science & ML
Monitoring
CI/CD
Stakeholder Communication
Prototyping
Infrastructure as Code
Agile & Scrum
Product Design